

CONTACTS



Planaltina, Brazil



leandro.araujo020984@gmail.com



+55 61 993003011

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Science Universidade Federal do Pará

Bachelor in Computer Science Universidade Federal do Pará

SOFT SKILLS

- Web Developement
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React
- Vue.js
- Figma
- Laravel
- Django
- HTML5
- CSS
- Tailwind CSS
- TypeScript
- Angular
- NextJS
- NestJS

Leandro Araujo

Senior Frontend Developer

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Over a 14 year career in web development, working in the Brazil and Latin America, I have comprehensive experience with React, Vue.js, and other frameworks. Great understanding of JavaScript, Node.js, Laravel, Django. Experience in responsive and mobile WEB development. Works with client-side and distributed development teams. Experience with web systems running on various OS and browsers, including older versions. Strong understanding of CSS pre-processors (SASS / SCSS) and frameworks (Tailwind CSS).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

2018.05 - 2023.01

DIGITALSUITS - Austin, Texas

Employing over 60 specialists, DIGITALSUITS is one of the rising development company in America.

At this company, I worked in a Frontend Developer role about 5 years and I participated as a team member to build a MVP web site for a product view company.

- Provided a role of myself as a development team lead where my main responsibility
 was to create a scalable architecture and related activities so that the company can
 generate maximum revenue by building high quality web applications
- Developed A/B tests using Optimizely and React and API integration
- Carried out a majority of development in Vue.js and Nodejs

Senior Frontend Developer

2014.03 - 2018.02

PLATHANUS - Palhoça, Brazil.

PLATHANUS is a famous web and mobile development group in the United States, with over 100 talents.

In 2017, the PLATHANUS launched a successful web application called PollThePeople with the function of head-to-head survey.

At PollThePeople, I was part of the team that design intuitive and fully-responsive user interfaces in React.

As a PollThePeople team member I

- Designed PollThePeople premium plan features along with a small team of 2 UX designers and 2 Front-End Developers
- Developed and maintained multiple websites using React/Redux, Material-UI

Frontend Developer

2009.3 - 2014.01

NEXTLY - Vitória, Brazil

Full cycle software development company operating in the international market. It was the first place which give me a shot to grow my skills. During these days, I

- Collected and filtered early adopter users' feedback
- Presented users' requests for new features to the company's board
- Built reusable and clean React.js, Vue.js components with high-quality, optimized code and best practices

LIFE PHILOSOPHY

The secret of success is to do
The common thing uncommonly well.

INTEREST

Sports and Music

LANGUAGES

- English- Fluent
- Portuguese- Native o bilingual